<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-05-26T14:55:06+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tessa Power</title><subtitle>Have you tried turning it off and on again?</subtitle><author><name>Tessa Power</name></author><entry><title type="html">How I got here.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-i-got-here/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I got here." /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-i-got-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-i-got-here/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-2015&quot;&gt;In 2015…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was travelling around Europe with a friend for three months. We were staying in Stuttgart, Germany, where the company my friend worked as a software engineer was also based. With too much time on my hands, and little German ability, I hung around the apartment while he worked. Sometimes, for a change of scenery, I would hang around the office. The office wasn’t huge—there were around 10 employees—and they were all working on an iOS app, a to-do list.
One can only do so much quiet reading and make so much pizza. I started to talk to the other engineers, asking a lot of questions and peering over shoulders at the brightly-coloured mess on their screens. Using a computer is easy, but I had put anything to do with computer science in the &lt;em&gt;too-hard-basket&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend suggested I try to follow a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/referencelibrary/GettingStarted/DevelopiOSAppsSwift/&quot;&gt;Swift tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. With no prior CS experience, I spent a while scratching my head and googling definitions. Following the tutorial wasn’t as simple as I initially thought. I had to be creative as well as logical, which seemed counter-intuitive at the time. After a few hours, I had hacked together an app, which I proudly showed my friend. It displayed a simple table view of recipes, and only ran on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that day, I didn’t think software development was within my “scope”. I think back sometimes, and how I remember it fondly. In reality, it looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;middle&quot; alt=&quot;Concentrating Tessa&quot; src=&quot;\assets\concentrating-tessa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;	&lt;img align=&quot;middle&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Tessa&quot; src=&quot;\assets\happy-tessa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks grim, but I was enjoying myself, I swear. The seed had been planted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-late-2016&quot;&gt;In late 2016…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved with my friend (who was now my partner) from London to Germany. I wanted to learn the language, the culture, and try to get into a University to study Computer Science. From 2017 to 2018, I attended the Cooperative State University of Baden-Württemberg. As it turns out, studying in a foreign language in a technical field is extremely difficult! I was wildly under-prepared and out of my depth. After a year of study, I joined an early-stage startup, not quite sure what I could do, but eager to put in the hard yards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve been working in the tech industry doing interesting things. Being part of an early-stage startup meant that I got to wear many hats: customer support, junior website hacker, iOS app tester and deployer, coffee-maker, marketer, social media guru, and cycle courier to name a few. We worked 14 hour days, spent a lot of time playing ping-pong, saw a few cycling injuries, and even shifted countries! It was a stressful, fun, busy, exciting, and happy time, but after 18 months the company shut down. I moved onto a more mature startup, where I put the lessons I learned into my role as a Product Associate. The role was exciting, and my teammates were marvelous, but it was not where I wanted to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;earlier-this-year&quot;&gt;Earlier this year…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to return to study—I want to finish off that Computer Science degree! My partner (now husband) and I also decided that studying via distance (online) would be the best option. This means we can live anywhere we’d like—so we chose New Zealand.  It’s not only where we are both from, but also a beautiful country. In July 2020, I begin my first semester at Massey University. Until then, I’ll be working on small personal projects to learn c++, and other technical skills. I wanted somewhere to document my journey, and the result is what you’re reading now. In later posts, you’ll be able to read about my personal projects and the lessons learnt.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tessa Power</name></author><summary type="html">In 2015… I was travelling around Europe with a friend for three months. We were staying in Stuttgart, Germany, where the company my friend worked as a software engineer was also based. With too much time on my hands, and little German ability, I hung around the apartment while he worked. Sometimes, for a change of scenery, I would hang around the office. The office wasn’t huge—there were around 10 employees—and they were all working on an iOS app, a to-do list. One can only do so much quiet reading and make so much pizza. I started to talk to the other engineers, asking a lot of questions and peering over shoulders at the brightly-coloured mess on their screens. Using a computer is easy, but I had put anything to do with computer science in the too-hard-basket. My friend suggested I try to follow a Swift tutorial. With no prior CS experience, I spent a while scratching my head and googling definitions. Following the tutorial wasn’t as simple as I initially thought. I had to be creative as well as logical, which seemed counter-intuitive at the time. After a few hours, I had hacked together an app, which I proudly showed my friend. It displayed a simple table view of recipes, and only ran on my iPhone. Before that day, I didn’t think software development was within my “scope”. I think back sometimes, and how I remember it fondly. In reality, it looked something like this: It looks grim, but I was enjoying myself, I swear. The seed had been planted. In late 2016… I moved with my friend (who was now my partner) from London to Germany. I wanted to learn the language, the culture, and try to get into a University to study Computer Science. From 2017 to 2018, I attended the Cooperative State University of Baden-Württemberg. As it turns out, studying in a foreign language in a technical field is extremely difficult! I was wildly under-prepared and out of my depth. After a year of study, I joined an early-stage startup, not quite sure what I could do, but eager to put in the hard yards. Since then, I’ve been working in the tech industry doing interesting things. Being part of an early-stage startup meant that I got to wear many hats: customer support, junior website hacker, iOS app tester and deployer, coffee-maker, marketer, social media guru, and cycle courier to name a few. We worked 14 hour days, spent a lot of time playing ping-pong, saw a few cycling injuries, and even shifted countries! It was a stressful, fun, busy, exciting, and happy time, but after 18 months the company shut down. I moved onto a more mature startup, where I put the lessons I learned into my role as a Product Associate. The role was exciting, and my teammates were marvelous, but it was not where I wanted to be. Earlier this year… I decided to return to study—I want to finish off that Computer Science degree! My partner (now husband) and I also decided that studying via distance (online) would be the best option. This means we can live anywhere we’d like—so we chose New Zealand. It’s not only where we are both from, but also a beautiful country. In July 2020, I begin my first semester at Massey University. Until then, I’ll be working on small personal projects to learn c++, and other technical skills. I wanted somewhere to document my journey, and the result is what you’re reading now. In later posts, you’ll be able to read about my personal projects and the lessons learnt.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, I’m Tessa.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, I'm Tessa." /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00+12:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;-whoami&quot;&gt;$ whoami&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, I’m 27. I’m from New Zealand, but I’ve lived in a few different countries and learned a few different languages. I only know enough to order an ice cream in Italy and a coffee in France—German is the language I can speak mostly fluently. I’m studying a Bachelor of Science at Massey University—my major is Computer Science and my minor is Math. In 3 years, I want to work in the video games industry as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that I will passionately talk your ear off about about are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Languages (human and computer);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video games (especially Zelda, Pokemon, Final Fantasy IX through X-2 and Kingdom Hearts);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploring the outdoors (and running around in it);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rock climbing;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scuba Diving; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spicy food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have feedback, know any bad jokes, or know something I should write about—just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=@dearesttessi%20&quot; title=&quot;Tweet Tessa&quot;&gt;tweet me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tessa Power</name></author><summary type="html">$ whoami At the time of writing, I’m 27. I’m from New Zealand, but I’ve lived in a few different countries and learned a few different languages. I only know enough to order an ice cream in Italy and a coffee in France—German is the language I can speak mostly fluently. I’m studying a Bachelor of Science at Massey University—my major is Computer Science and my minor is Math. In 3 years, I want to work in the video games industry as a developer. Things that I will passionately talk your ear off about about are: Languages (human and computer); Video games (especially Zelda, Pokemon, Final Fantasy IX through X-2 and Kingdom Hearts); Exploring the outdoors (and running around in it); Rock climbing; Scuba Diving; and Spicy food. If you have feedback, know any bad jokes, or know something I should write about—just tweet me!</summary></entry></feed>